[
  {
    "question": "Plant – cannot complete their ______ cycles without each other.",
    "answer": "life"
  },
  {
    "question": "The moth deposits its ______ in the locule of the ovary.",
    "answer": "eggs"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flower, in turn, gets ______ by the moth.",
    "answer": "pollinated"
  },
  {
    "question": "The larvae of the moth come out of the eggs as the ______ start developing.",
    "answer": "seeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flowers of ______, Mango, Peepal, Coriander, Papaya, Onion, Lobia, Cotton, Tobacco, Rose, Lemon, Eucalyptus, Banana can be observed for pollinators.",
    "answer": "Cucumber"
  },
  {
    "question": "You’ll have to patiently observe the flowers over a few ______ and at different times of the day.",
    "answer": "days"
  },
  {
    "question": "Such floral visitors are referred to as pollen/nectar ______.",
    "answer": "robbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Majority of flowering plants produce ______ flowers.",
    "answer": "hermaphrodite"
  },
  {
    "question": "Continued self-pollination results in ______ depression.",
    "answer": "inbreeding"
  },
  {
    "question": "In some species, pollen release and stigma receptivity are not ______.",
    "answer": "synchronised"
  },
  {
    "question": "Either the pollen is released before the stigma becomes ______.",
    "answer": "receptive"
  },
  {
    "question": "The anther and stigma are placed at different positions so that the pollen cannot come in contact with the ______ of the same flower.",
    "answer": "stigma"
  },
  {
    "question": "The third device to prevent inbreeding is ______.",
    "answer": "self-incompatibility"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-incompatibility prevents self-pollen from fertilising the ______.",
    "answer": "ovules"
  },
  {
    "question": "Another device to prevent self-pollination is the production of ______ flowers.",
    "answer": "unisexual"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ______, both male and female flowers are present on the same plant.",
    "answer": "monoecious"
  },
  {
    "question": "Examples of monoecious plants are ______ and maize.",
    "answer": "castor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ______, male and female flowers are present on different plants.",
    "answer": "dioecy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Papaya is an example of a ______ plant.",
    "answer": "dioecious"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dioecy prevents both ______ and geitonogamy.",
    "answer": "autogamy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pollination does not guarantee the transfer of the right type of ______.",
    "answer": "pollen"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pistil has the ability to ______ the pollen.",
    "answer": "recognise"
  },
  {
    "question": "If pollen is of the right type, the pistil accepts the pollen and promotes ______ events.",
    "answer": "post-pollination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Post-pollination events lead to ______.",
    "answer": "fertilization"
  }
]
